genealogybank.com 2016-11-01

# Privacy Policy - GenealogyBank

**Privacy Policy**

**Last Modified:** July 26, 2015

**This Privacy Policy discloses the general privacy practices for web sites owned and/or operated by NewsBank, Inc., NewsBank Media Services, Inc. and their affiliated companies (collectively, “NewsBank”)** **, which** **includes this site at GenealogyBank.com **. It does not apply to any information that may be obtained offline. Any changes to this policy will be posted on this page with an updated** modified date as shown above, so please check this page routinely for updates.**

**Information Collected**

_Voluntary Submissions Only._

While visiting any of the NewsBank web sites (collectively, the “Site”), we may ask you to register and/or provide information that personally identifies you (“Personal Information”) for purposes of interacting with the Site. Such Personal Information may include, but is not limited to, your name, phone number, street address, and e-mail address. On any page that collects Personal Information, we will specifically describe what information is required in order to provide you with the product or service, enter you in the promotion you have requested, or respond to your inquiry or comment. The only way we learn Personal Information is if you specifically and voluntarily submit it to us. While we may log IP addresses (the location of a computer on the Internet) from visitors for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes and to determine site usage, IP addresses do not contain Personal Information.

_Information We Collect Through Automatic Data Collection Technologies_

As you navigate through and interact with our Site, we may use automatic data collection technologies to collect certain information about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns, including:

  * Details of your visits to our Site, including traffic data, location data, logs and other communication data and the resources that you access and use on the Site.
  * Information about your computer and Internet connection, including your IP address, operating system and browser type.

We also may use these technologies to collect information about your online activities over time and across third-party websites or other online services (behavioral tracking). See below for information on how you can opt out of behavioral tracking on this Site and how we respond to web browser signals and other mechanisms that enable consumers to exercise choice about behavioral tracking.

The information we collect automatically may be associated with personal information we collect in other ways or receive from third parties. It helps us to improve our Site and to deliver a better and more personalized service, including by enabling us to:

  * Estimate our audience size and usage patterns;
  * Store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Site according to your individual interests;
  * Speed up your searches; and
  * Recognize you when you return to our Site.

The technologies we use for this automatic data collection may include:

  * Cookies (or browser cookies). A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Site.
  * Third Parties’ Cookies _._ We may use an advertising server, developed by a third party, to display ads, which may contain cookies from third-party advertisers. We do not have access to these cookies or any information in them. We encourage you to contact any advertiser and consult its privacy policy for more information on cookies used by such advertisers. Links from other web sites that appear on the Site may also send cookies; but we do not control such activities.
  * Flash Cookies. Certain features of our Site may use local stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from and on our Site. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies. For information about managing your privacy and security settings for Flash cookies, see Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information.
  * Web Beacons. Pages of the Site and our e-mails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs. pixel tags and single-pixel gifs) that permit NewsBank, for example, to count users who have visited those pages or opened an e-mail and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity).
  * We use Google Analytics, which is a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies to help the Site analyze how individuals use the Site. We also use Google’s Universal Analytics and Google Advertiser Features, including audience demographic and interest reports in connection with such services.  The non-personal information generated by the cookie about your use of the Site will be transmitted to and stored by Google. Google will use this information for the purposes of evaluating your use of the Site, compiling reports on Site activity for our purpose, evaluation and providing other services relating to the Site activity and Internet usage. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may disable cookies within your browser as described above, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Site. By using this Site, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. For certain browsers, you can also prevent Google from collecting information (including your IP address) via cookies and processing this information by downloading this browser plugin and installing it: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

_Do Not Track - NAI_

Because we may track Site usage information through the use of cookies, pixels and other tracking mechanisms, your selection of the “Do Not Track” option provided by your browser may not have any effect on our collection of cookie information. The only way to completely “opt out” of the collection of any information through cookies or other tracking technology is to actively manage the settings on your browser to delete and disable cookies and other tracking/recording tools. However, getting a “Do Not Track” signal to work as you might want is difficult.  Using browsers as an example, not all tracking technologies can be controlled by browsers; unique aspects of your browser might be recognizable even if you disable a tracking technology; not all settings will necessarily last or be effective; even if a setting is effective for one purpose data still may be collected for another; and even if one website observes a “Do Not Track” signal, that website usually will not be able to control other websites.

We do not control third parties’ collection or use of your information to serve interest-based advertising. However these third parties may provide you with ways to choose not to have your information collected or used in this way. You can opt out of receiving targeted ads from members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) on the NAI’s website.

**How Do We Use Personal Information?**

We may use your Personal Information, such as your e-mail address or mailing address, to contact you regarding products and/or services that we believe may be of interest to you, or to respond to an inquiry from you regarding the information that we have collected, or to respond to your comments and suggestions. You will at all times be able to opt out from receiving advertising communications from us, either by specifically opting out of these communications or by deleting your profile from our database. Please refer to “Opting-Out” for details.

When you sign up for a service we offer on the Site, we may share your Personal Information with third-party service providers, such as credit card processors, shipping companies and fulfillment services, in order to provide the service. These third parties are required to comply with this policy and protect your information in the same way we do. They are not permitted to retain or use Personal Information for any purpose unrelated to providing the service you requested.

NewsBank may also offer services and opportunities from unaffiliated third parties on the Site (information notification services, personalized news alerts, sweepstakes, etc.). If you choose to use these optional services or opportunities, we may provide some of your Personal Information to these parties. Some of these third parties may also collect their own Personal Information. We encourage you to check the applicable privacy policy for that portion of the Site prior to disclosing Personal Information. Please see “Party Collecting the Information” for further reference. From time to time we may also become aware of third parties offering services or opportunities separately from this Site that we believe may be of interest to you, and we may furnish Personal Information to such parties to enable them to inform you about those services or opportunities.

In addition, we reserve the right to disclose Personal Information when needed to comply with the law or a legal process, to cooperate with investigations of purported unlawful activities, and to identify persons violating the law. In the event of a sale of part or all of NewsBank’s or its affiliates’ stock or assets, our databases, including any Personal Information, will be transferred to the new owner.

**Party Collecting the Information**

This Privacy Policy only addresses the collection, use and dissemination of Personal Information you submit to NewsBank via the Site, and not any Personal Information you may disclose to other parties (including via third-party services or promotions offered on or through the Site). Different policies may apply to Personal Information you give to such third parties, and NewsBank shall not be responsible for the use or dissemination of any such Personal Information.

Our Site may operate as part of a larger group of sites, and may carry co-branded pages. In addition, other sites may use the Site’s or NewsBank’s name. Since NewsBank does not control the privacy policies of third parties, you are subject to the privacy customs and policies, if any, of such third parties, and NewsBank shall not be responsible for the use or dissemination of your Personal Information by such parties. Therefore, we encourage you to ask questions and review those parties’ privacy policies before you disclose your Personal Information to others.

**Links To Other Materials**

Third party sites linked to and from the Site are not necessarily under the control of NewsBank. NewsBank shall have no responsibilities or liabilities whatsoever for the content or privacy practices of any such linked site or any link or linking program at any time. NewsBank does not necessarily endorse companies (or related products or services) to or from which the Site is linked. If you decide to access any of the third party sites linked to the Site, you do so entirely at your own risk.

**Children’s Privacy**

NewsBank cares about the safety of children and their use of the Internet. Therefore, in accordance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, we will never knowingly request or solicit personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without verifiable parental consent.  Please contact us immediately at [privacypolicy@genealogybank.com](mailto:privacypolicy@genealogybank.com) if you believe personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 13 is stored in our system.

**Opting-Out**

We respect your privacy and ability to choose whether to share information with us and any third party. You may choose to “opt-out” of sharing Personal Information in several ways. When choosing to use certain features or services on the Site, you can choose whether to share optional Personal Information in connection with the feature or service. If you receive communications from us that you prefer not to receive, you may opt out from receiving these communications by contacting us at [privacypolicy@genealogybank.com](mailto:privacypolicy@genealogybank.com).

You may “opt-out” altogether from providing Personal Information to us by not registering on the Site and thereby not providing Personal Information. You may also choose at a later date to confirm the accuracy of your Personal Information that you have provided to us by contacting us at [privacypolicy@genealogybank.com](mailto:privacypolicy@genealogybank.com).

Certain portions of the Site and certain services provided on the Site, however, do require registration in order to access or use these areas and services. If you choose not to register or provide certain information, these areas will not be accessible to you.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (‘Shine the Light law’) permits California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, a list of the third parties to whom we have disclosed personal information (as defined under that statute) of that California resident, for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year and the categories of personal information that was disclosed to them. If you are a California resident and you wish to make such a request, you may contact us at [privacypolicy@genealogybank.com](mailto:privacypolicy@genealogybank.com), or write to us at the address provided below in the Contact Information section.

**Security**

NewsBank maintains industry standard safeguards to help protect the security, integrity, and privacy of the Personal Information that you provide to NewsBank. Please understand, however, that there are inherent security risks in any online medium, and no guarantee can be made against unauthorized access by third parties.

**How To Contact Us**

If you have any questions or comments about our Privacy Policy, please e-mail us at [privacypolicy@genealogybank.com](mailto:privacypolicy@genealogybank.com).

**Changes To Policy**

NewsBank reserves the right to modify the terms of this policy at any time and in our sole discretion, by posting a changes to this page. Your continued use of the Site following our posting of a changes will constitute binding acceptance of those changes.
